A hero will be revealed.
Spider-Man 2 is a action, adventure, science fiction film directed by Sam Raimi.
Peter Parker is going through a major identity crisis.
Burned out from being Spider-Man, he decides to shelve his superhero alter ego, which
leaves the city suffering in the wake of carnage left by the evil Doc Ock.
In the meantime, Parker still can't act on his feelings for Mary
Jane Watson, a girl he's loved since childhood.
A certain anger begins to brew in his best friend Harry Osborn as well...
Spider-Man / Peter Parker, played by Tobey Maguire.
Mary Jane Watson, played by Kirsten Dunst.
Harry Osborn, played by James Franco.
Doc Ock / Otto Octavius, played by Alfred Molina.
May Parker, played by Rosemary Harris.
J. Jonah Jameson, played by J.K. Simmons.
Spider-Man 2 is a 2004 American superhero film based on
the Marvel Comics character Spider-Man.
Directed by Sam Raimi and written by Alvin Sargent from a story conceived by Michael Chabon and the writing team of Alfred
Gough and Miles Millar, it is the second installment in Raimi's Spider-Man trilogy, following the 2002 film.
The film stars Tobey Maguire as Peter Parker / Spider-Man, alongside Kirsten
Dunst, James Franco, Alfred Molina, Rosemary Harris, and Donna Murphy.
Peter Parker fights to stop scientist Dr.
Otto Octavius from recreating a dangerous experiment,
while also dealing with a personal crisis.
Principal photography began in April 2003 in New York
City and also took place in Los Angeles.
Reshoots took place later that year and concluded in February 2004.
Danny Elfman returned to compose the score.
Spider-Man 2 premiered at the Mann Village Theater in Los Angeles on June 25, 2004,
and was released in both conventional and IMAX theaters on June 30.
It received acclaim from critics, who praised its emotional weight and visual
effects, the performances of Maguire and Molina, and Raimi's directing.
The film grossed $795.9 million worldwide, making it the
third-highest-grossing film of the year.
It was selected by the American Film Institute as
one of the top 10 films of 2004.
Spider-Man 2 won Best Visual Effects at the 77th Academy Awards, and was
also nominated for Best Sound Mixing and Best Sound Editing.
It received five awards at the Saturn Awards, including
Best Fantasy Film and Best Director.
Its success led to Spider-Man 3 (2007).
The Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU) film Spider-Man: No Way Home (2021) explored the concept of the multiverse to
connect the previous Spider-Man films to the MCU, with Maguire and Molina reprising their roles.
The film explores themes of new york city, dual identity,
love of one's life, secret identity, superhero.
The tone is thought_provoking.